<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jonchoi.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jonchoi.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-11T16:34:39-07:00</updated><id>https://jonchoi.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">exploring entropy.</title><subtitle>I write stuff here.
</subtitle><author><name>Jon Choi</name></author><entry><title type="html">Enter the Crypto Idea Maze</title><link href="https://jonchoi.com/cryptoideamaze/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enter the Crypto Idea Maze" /><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://jonchoi.com/cryptoideamaze</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jonchoi.com/cryptoideamaze/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt;  It’s early in the game for crypto, and an idea maze helps us dig deeper and discern between compelling adoption paths and dead ends.  Bitcoin then Ethereum catalyzed excitement for “crypto” broadly, and the industry is debating the merits of “sound money,” “web3” and “open finance.”  While each share the same ethos of disintermediation, they require different features to succeed and are competing against different alternatives.  Inheriting not only the ethos of decentralization but also the technical tradeoffs of its predecessors has resulted in an underlying cognitive dissonance.  The way to resolve the dissonance is to forget the familiar narratives, and instead to examine: the novel features of the technology, who the core customers are, who is failing to serve them now and why there can be a compelling new product today.  Let’s enter the crypto idea maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.stanstedpark.co.uk/public/images/Grounds/Maze_from_above.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What is an idea maze?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before the Maze: Bitcoin then Smart Contracts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter the Maze: The Three Theses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cognitive Dissonance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers, Alternatives and Intermediate Utility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How are your customers faring without you?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Timing of It All&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing What’s Next
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sound Money: In Code We Trust&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Web3: UX vs Trust&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open Finance: Bearer vs Registered Instruments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploring Assumptions and Rebuttals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How can we contribute today?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-idea-maze&quot;&gt;The Idea Maze&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdixon.org/2013/08/04/the-idea-maze/&quot;&gt;idea maze&lt;/a&gt; metaphor stems from the fact that a technology trend has various adoption paths that lead to varying levels of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good startup ideas are well developed, multi-year plans that contemplate many possible paths according to how the world changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In an exuberant time, it’s often tempting to run straight for the entrance to take the lead, but chances of success will be much greater for teams that have a rough map that guides them.&lt;/strong&gt; Being a student of the technology, its history as well as learnings from other mazes will help us map out the maze.  It will give teams more clarity in pursuing or avoiding certain target customers, product features, and to market strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A good founder is capable of anticipating which turns lead to treasure and which lead to certain death. A bad founder is just running to the entrance of (say) the “movies/music/filesharing/P2P” maze or the “photosharing” maze without any sense for the history of the industry, the players in the maze, the casualties of the past, and the technologies that are likely to move walls and change assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a sports fan and an experienced coach are both watching a game and see the same inputs, but they notice vastly different levels of detail.  While a sports fan can be excited about what’s happening, the good coach can see how to navigate the opposing team, how certain changes of the roster or formation could be effective, and reliably affect the course of the game.  Technology and adoption seem no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feels especially salient for crypto because it is multidisciplinary and requires cooperation among many stakeholders across industries and geographies.  Also, mapping the idea maze seems especially more important early in the lifecycle of a platform (e.g. web, social media, mobile).  Because vision and ethos are currently leading ahead of adoption, it is not clear from this vantage point which approaches are headed towards a market with strong demand and sustainable economics vs a dead end (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; early).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I’d like to share a rough outline of how I construct my crypto idea maze (open source all the things!).  We will focus on challenges in reconciling core assumptions of various crypto theses, and we will save specific adoption paths (go to market + geo) and deep-dives on applications for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;review-before-the-maze&quot;&gt;Review: Before the Maze.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-the-beginning-there-was-bitcoin&quot;&gt;In the beginning**, there was Bitcoin.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;initial intent&lt;/em&gt; for Bitcoin is very clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A purely peer-to-peer version of electronic cash would allow online payments to be sent directly from one party to another without going through a financial institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an experiment in creating a payment network that removed the need for mediation, in order to (1) reduce the fees of digital commerce and (2) remove the need for sharing more identity information than required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Completely non-reversible transactions are not really possible, since financial institutions cannot avoid mediating disputes. The cost of mediation increases transaction costs, limiting the minimum practical transaction size and cutting off the possibility for small casual transactions, and there is a broader cost in the loss of ability to make non-reversible payments for non-reversible services. &lt;strong&gt;With the possibility of reversal, the need for trust spreads&lt;/strong&gt;. Merchants must be wary of their customers, hassling them for more information than they would otherwise need. A certain percentage of fraud is accepted as unavoidable. These costs and payment uncertainties can be avoided in person by using physical currency, but no mechanism exists to make payments over a communications channel without a trusted party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was created to provide a way to transact without identity or a trusted intermediary.  It began as the currency of choice for technologists &amp;amp; hackers, libertarians, black market users, cross-border remittances, and the oppressed (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; Venezuela).  This was especially timely given the government bail out of banks that took on excess risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prominent features that came from having no trusted intermediary were censorship resistance (very expensive to change or stop a transaction) and immutable monetary policy (can’t “print” more resources unilaterally).  In order to do so, it uses a peer-to-peer architecture and a novel economic incentive mechanism (proof of work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that &lt;strong&gt;the innovation explicitly traded off efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; in order to provide censorship resistance and flexible membership set of participants (anyone can join or leave the network at any time).  We will come back to this, but in the meanwhile something else captured the attention of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;** To be fair, Bitcoin was preceded by Digicash (Chaum 1989) and bit gold (Szabo 1998).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;then-there-were-smart-contract-platforms&quot;&gt;Then there were smart contract platforms.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A smart contract is a computerized transaction protocol that executes the terms of a contract. The general objectives of smart contract design are to satisfy common contractual conditions (such as payment terms, liens, confidentiality, and even enforcement), minimize exceptions both malicious and accidental, and minimize the need for trusted intermediaries. Related economic goals include lowering fraud loss, arbitration and enforcement costs, and other transaction costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of smart contracts have been around for quite some time (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fon.hum.uva.nl/rob/Courses/InformationInSpeech/CDROM/Literature/LOTwinterschool2006/szabo.best.vwh.net/smart.contracts.html&quot;&gt;coined and popularized by Nick Szabo in 1994&lt;/a&gt;, quoted above), and the demand to implement smart contract capability had a resurgence through the Bitcoin community (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rsk.co/&quot;&gt;RSK&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Colored_Coins&quot;&gt;Colored Coins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.omni.foundation/2013/11/29/a-brief-history-of-mastercoin/&quot;&gt;Mastercoin&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&quot;https://vitalik.ca/general/2017/09/14/prehistory.html&quot;&gt;One person working on Mastercoin was Vitalik Buterin&lt;/a&gt;, who thought the idea of extending the Bitcoin protocol was exciting yet a limited implementation of the full potential of smart contracts.  His ideas diverged enough from the priorities of the Mastercoin team that it wasn’t being implemented in Mastercoin, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20131219030753/http://vitalik.ca/ethereum.html&quot;&gt;Ethereum was born&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while Bitcoin achieved consensus over the state of a transaction ledger (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; accounting), this branch of the movement began experimenting with consensus on the state of a computer replicated in a distributed network around the world (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; distributed virtual machine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that, while cloud computing focused on getting distributed computers to do things quickly and efficiently to serve demanding applications within a trusted setting (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; datacenter controlled by one party), decentralized computing focuses on allowing computers that don’t necessarily trust each other to agree on a shared state of a computer.  While adding computers to a cloud infrastructure makes the network more computationally productive (in varying degrees depending on technical architecture), decentralized infrastructure is instead optimized to maintain a certain level of “trustlessness” (or threshold for bad actors).  Therefore, adding computers to a decentralized network–while adding complexity–doesn’t add much, if any, computational throughput of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite those limitations, Ethereum was attractive for many reasons but in particular: (1) it was now very easy to create and deploy uncensorable smart contracts into production (the awareness around Bitcoin mining certainly was an added catalyst for building a lively early mining community) and (2) people could now imagine, “if it’s possible to transact without intermediaries, what other interactions could we also manage without intermediaries?”  The simple analogy evolved from a digital “vending machine” that is owned by one party (and could thus be taken down, &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; Paypal) to one that is not owned by anyone, is unstoppable and still accessible to anyone in the world with an Internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as Bitcoin was timely for the zeitgeist of the financial crisis.  Ethereum was timely for consumers losing trust in various intermediaries, namely banks (&lt;a href=&quot;https://money.cnn.com/2016/09/08/investing/wells-fargo-created-phony-accounts-bank-fees/index.html&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2016/06/23/bank-america-pay-430m-settlements/86284438/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) and Internet giants (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/business/consumer/trust-facebook-has-dropped-51-percent-cambridge-analytica-scandal-n867011&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2015/02/why-im-saying-goodbye-to-apple-google-and-microsoft/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;).  This distributed computer concept generated excitement because the architecture has deep implications on possibilities to disintermediate those trust-required intermediary industries.  Some representative ideas/examples were decentralized Uber and Airbnb (web3) as well as decentralized platforms for lending, derivatives and startup investing (open finance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have experiments that replace the simple transaction ledger in Bitcoin with various forms of distributed computation (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; Ethereum, EOS, Dfinity, Tezos, Stellar).  This sets the stage for the Crypto Idea Maze (2018 vintage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-the-crypto-idea-maze&quot;&gt;Enter the Crypto Idea Maze.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a fascinating part of the crypto idea maze in 2018; we have the proliferation of smart contract platforms, excitement around web3 &amp;amp; open finance, and the Bitcoin &amp;amp; privacy coin communities coalescing around the sound money narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are the crypto theses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound money&lt;/strong&gt; – “Trustless money” that cannot be inflated by any trusted authority such as a central bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3&lt;/strong&gt; – “Trustless internet” where Internet architecture is free of trusted centralized data &amp;amp; service monopolies.  Users have more control over their data and Internet usage.  These networks also compensate participants for economic value generated in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open finance&lt;/strong&gt; – “Trustless financial systems” that extend cryptocurrency to provide open software primitives for equities, debt, derivatives, checking accounts, remittances, work contracts, retirement accounts, property &lt;em&gt;etc&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Open to feedback).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, the term “crypto” means different things to different people, and yet we all refer to this one word as a catchall (sorry, cryptographers! :\ ).  This has been a boon for a budding interdisciplinary community but also much miscommunication among &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blind_men_and_an_elephant&quot;&gt;blind men describing an elephant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they all share the same ethos of disintermediation (respectively of government banks, big Internet giants, and commercial banks/fintechs), we will find that there is significant cognitive dissonance in having a shared set of technical tradeoffs across implementing disparate theses with different needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hello-cognitive-dissonance&quot;&gt;Hello, cognitive dissonance!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive dissonance&lt;/em&gt; – The state of having inconsistent thoughts, beliefs, or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, many have come to realize that it is not easy to reconcile winning forms of sound money, web3 and open finance under one technology. This is likely due to divergent underlying assumptions of the theses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt; Adding a feature on top of a platform optimized to remove said feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt; Inheriting tradeoffs designed for another need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, &lt;strong&gt;we are building identity and “censorship abilities” on top of a platform optimized for not having identity and censorship&lt;/strong&gt;.  The potential problem here is: intuitively, that’s far from resembling the most efficient architecture (this is an uncontroversial statement, even to core devs of these technologies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a more fundamental level, this dissonance exists because many smart contract public blockchains inherit tradeoffs made by Bitcoin: the network architecture, replication scheme, incentive mechanisms.  Those tradeoffs absorbed many orders of magnitude of replication inefficiency and “SLAs” (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; throughput, availability, predictable pricing) to make it difficult to (1) not require identity and (2) remove the need for a central entity that can censor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the question becomes why should things with disparate user end goals (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; web3 / open finance) share the infrastructure tradeoffs of another product need (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; sound money).  There still may be compelling reasons why (as even one change in assumption can quickly change the outcome), but it’s definitely not a gimme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-means-to-an-end&quot;&gt;A Means to an End&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the use case of money, those were excellent new features.  No one can change the rules of the game on you, doesn’t matter who you are, where you are, the value you have won’t be diluted by unforeseen increase in money supply, is unstoppable by a single party and doesn’t require to know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However those features are not inherently valuable; they are valuable due to serving a specific user need.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, those features are good or bad depending on what service one is trying to provide.  For example, the downside of introducing identity is discrimination, but the upside is reputation.  Analogously, the downside of having central entity is censorship/liability, but the upside is quality service and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the various theses share technological primitives and ethos of disintermediation, we will explore what this means in the context of the diverging needs of their end users.  This is the crux of the maze today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;define-the-way-out-of-the-maze&quot;&gt;Define the way out of the Maze.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, there’s never been a higher premium for the ability to think independently.  We ingest narrative after narrative on a daily basis on Twitter, and conflicting assumption sets of these narratives are exactly what made this maze more complicated (be skeptical of this post too!).  The only way out of the maze is to think independently about the customer need and what features those needs will demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will discuss in more detail in the section below, but let’s first take a look at the criteria in the rubric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customer-centric compass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is the customer and the stakeholders in their experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Who is the core customer? (define personas / markets)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What % of the world is affected?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the level of “pain” per person affected?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How do people join the network and why do they stay in the network?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer’s counterparty
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is it a one-to-one?  Is it one-to-many?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Does the counterparty need to have the same product need as the primary customer?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trusted intermediary
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Who do you depend on to enforce the rules?  Who could rule against you?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Atomic unit of success”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an ambiguous and multi-faceted product like crypto, it’s important to explicitly define the fundamental metric for customer satisfaction.  For Google, it’s a completed search.  For Uber, it’s a completed ride.  For owning a share of Apple, it might be return on equity and earnings per share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for USD, what is it?  For crypto networks, what is it?  We will discuss below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Next best alternative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethos-agnostic customers (aka “most people”) will be driven largely by &lt;strong&gt;a new feature’s benefit over its next best alternative&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, web search provided a convenient and fast alternative to seeking information from distant places. Google search provided a simpler and faster Internet search experience than Alta Vista, which was powerful and customizable but slower (perhaps optimized for the wrong feature given the early average user).  An early version of Uber provided a convenient way to call a black car to a location other than your usual office and travel in style.  Uber pool now provides an alternative to driving day-to-day or taking the bus/subway (in SF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tangible advantage over the next best alternative in serving a user need is exactly the forward momentum a product needs to improve and expand into adjacent services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intermediate Utility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intermediate utility refers to the usefulness of a network before it is sufficiently saturated (“if it takes over just 5% of a target market, do those 5% of users still derive utility in the meanwhile?”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things help the creation of a network at an early stage: (1) the discovery of active peers despite small network size and (2) how compelling those experiences are before the network fully matures.  Those are crucial factors in the “intermediate utility” of an early network.  Early adoption paths with intermediate utility are often the only ways to achieve a desired end state.  Contrapositive: certain desired end states are impossible/expensive to achieve because it’s difficult to have intermediate utility to bootstrap the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is an example of intermediate utility?  For example, Facebook was fun to use when I was in school (to communicate, signal and stalk within the school setting).  I didn’t use it too heavily but enough to keep me engaged.  That continued engagement of its early users for the early use case allowed Facebook to have a chance to further serve those users as well as expand into new markets.  If we had to wait years (or even just months) to get that initial usefulness, we never would have given it a shot–making more successful end states out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the fact that small portions of the broader target network can get utility from the early iterations of the technology is a huge benefit, allowing it to sustain intermediate size of networks without having to reflexively and virally grow all at once (check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tonysheng.com/price-flywheel&quot;&gt;Tony Sheng’s recent post&lt;/a&gt; on reflexivity in crypto).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intermediate utility serves as a “checkpoint” for the network to “save progress” as it grows.
 More broadly, a series of step-function gains in intermediate utility will ultimately set the stage for main stream adoption / “crossing the chasm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-badly-do-they-need-you&quot;&gt;How badly do they need you?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the theses are justifiably motivated by ethos, customer need and external catalysts will be the largest drivers of how this idea maze unfolds.  Let’s see how the criteria above map to the three crypto sub-theses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sound-money&quot;&gt;Sound money&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;:  Money that can be used to buy goods and store value, unaffected (and unprotected) by idiosyncratic government policy.  For example, shields user from incremental monetary easing, poor economic policy, corruption, and any other sovereign risk (issuer risk).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;:  “Internet money” in general made it possible to be unbound by physical realms (Digicash and Paypal still had this property, but had centralized settlement).  Proof of work distributed that settlement layer, making it unstoppable by any one jurisdiction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Customer&lt;/strong&gt;:  People that don’t have access to stable store of value (e.g. Venezuela/Argentina/Zimbabwe inflation. Another example is large number of Chinese investors buying up prime U.S. real estate to “park their money.”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counterparty&lt;/strong&gt;:  Person who is providing them the good/service they need (rent, food, other).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next best alternatives&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;  SWIFT/ACH/Western Union and cash (transfer of wealth).  Gold and USD (store of wealth).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provider of next best alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;:  Government-registered banks, money transmitters, independent off-shore banks (store and transfer of wealth).  Central bank + enforcing government (provides the instrument and trust).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradeoff&lt;/strong&gt;:  Between acceptance by peers (merchants/peers) and trust of issuer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic unit of success&lt;/strong&gt;:  (1) Ability to pay for good/service, (2) Peace of mind around saving for future goods/services (no loss, low volatility)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate utility&lt;/strong&gt;:  Transactions only require two parties at a time.  Storing value requires everyone to be bought in passively (other people believe it), but requires only “single player mode” actively (you hold it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;:  Game theoretic deadlock in getting merchant and supply chain buy in for accepting a new currency.  Lack of stability due to difficulty in matching monetary policy (supply) to predicted adoption curve (demand).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;web3&quot;&gt;Web3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;:  Users have more ownership over their digital data.  Users are less vulnerable to value misalignment with service providers such as Google and Facebook.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;:  An Internet where users rely less on centralized services that custody our data to provide the fastest, smoothest, most convenient experience, and an Internet where data ownership and service provision are decoupled (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; public p2p blockchain architecture: Ethereum (+IPFS), “BYOData”: Blockstack, gossip protocol: Secure Scuttlebutt).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Customer&lt;/strong&gt;:  People underserved by the current Internet:  people that cannot express what they want (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Censorship_in_China&quot;&gt;China’s Internet&lt;/a&gt;), people that cannot access all of the information due to censorship/obfuscation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/&quot;&gt;Catalonia censorship&lt;/a&gt;), and people that don’t trust their service providers with their data (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/19/technology/facebook-cambridge-analytica-explained.html&quot;&gt;Facebook’s Cambridge Analytica scandal&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counterparty&lt;/strong&gt;:  Other peers consuming and producing data online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next best alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;:  Google, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram (the products).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provider of next best alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;:  Google, Facebook, Twitter, Amazon, Tencent, Alibaba, Baidu (the profit maximizing entities behind the products).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradeoff&lt;/strong&gt;:  Between UX and trust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic unit of success&lt;/strong&gt;:  To be able to reach a broad audience without being stopped (censorship resistant).  The user ultimately having more control over their data and its privacy/commercialization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate Utility&lt;/strong&gt;:  Closed loop networks with core customer base (“we’re all censored”) is likely small.  More interesting would be somehow to distribute web3 &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; demand to the existing &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; traffic of web2.  A strong indicative metric would be to see how much the web3 community is able to dogfood its own tech and derive utility (people in working in crypto full-time still use Twitter and Venmo).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;:  (1) Web3 is not just percentages or few multiples more expensive but in fact many orders of magnitude more expensive to store and serve, which means that price parity may come but is not imminent and (2) getting average users to choose web3 over convenience and familiarity of web2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;open-finance&quot;&gt;Open Finance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;:  Financial tools and products available today to high net worth individuals and large corporations becoming available and affordable to everyone (or financial products/access available in developed markets becoming available in frontier markets).  Ability to take your wealth / assets with you smoothly across financial service providers.  Ability to frictionlessly participate in foreign economic growth by participating in their financial markets, just as easy as you share data/information across borders today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;:  Unified data sources and protocols across financial institutions. Compliance, back office, repeated ledger management cost cutting via shared data structure/source and management.  Better underwriting of financial products via making the financial system more interoperable with the rest of the Internet.  This will help unlock cost of capital and cost of living arbitrage opportunities, which will transfer wealth from rent seekers to network participants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Customer&lt;/strong&gt;:  People that don’t have access to core financial products for wealth generation (out of price, no access, no awareness).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counterparty&lt;/strong&gt;:  Other people who are trying to bet on the future with you and want to exchange resources and risk/reward.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next best alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;:  Existing financial and banking services (marked by higher fees, stronger lock ins, slower service, trust and little incentive to improve service quickly).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provider of Next Best Alternative&lt;/strong&gt;:  Regional Banks, National Banks, Multinational Banks, specialized fintechs (SoFi, Robinhood, Simple).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradeoff&lt;/strong&gt;:  Between (a) legal protection, enforceability and compliance versus (b) lower cost, lighter touch intermediation, more access, and more openness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic unit of success&lt;/strong&gt;:  Ability to receive money today for promise of returning more money tomorrow.  Ability to lend/invest money today and to be able to receive it back with financial return in the future within the agreed risk parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate utility&lt;/strong&gt;:  While rates and counterparty discovery becomes significantly better as markets develop, one party receiving a loan from another party is immediately useful to both parties involved without a whole network being bootstrapped already.  That’s great for generating intermediate utility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;:  Most use cases require reputation/identity (recourse for bad actions, benefit for good history) and legal enforcement (guarantee property, enforce payment / penalty).
 Specifically, wrapping with legal enforceability means that it needs to have capital controls and identity (AML/KYC).  It also requires ability to change record of truth upon arbitration (“That’s actually legally mine, but I lost it / was hacked, can you restore it?”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;** Future version may have to split this section into crypto-native vs fiat-native open finance.  (“Crypto-native open finance” is the intersection of web3 and open finance.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timing&quot;&gt;Timing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;long-term-its-not-a-competition&quot;&gt;Long-term: It’s not a competition.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a long enough time horizon, these theses will ultimately coalesce.  As a quick mental exercise from the lens of each thesis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sound money: “Money is software.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web3: “Own data; get money for data →  Data is money.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open finance: “Financial services are software.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that software continues to &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2016/08/20/why-software-is-eating-the-world/&quot;&gt;eat the world&lt;/a&gt; over the next few decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;medium-term-repeating-musical-chairs&quot;&gt;Medium-term: Repeating musical chairs.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the decentralization ethos can catalyze adoption by creating a beachhead with a more accommodating user base (“I like privacy, so I’ll use Signal over iMessage despite lacking features”, “I like local businesses, so I’ll pay more at the bookstore than buy on Amazon”), but to get mainstream adoption, &lt;strong&gt;the traction on the beachhead has to fuel technological and product innovation that can target an ethos-neutral mainstream audience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early use cases with product-market fit will account for the vast majority of the early usage, and in turn will get the most customers, mindshare and resources.  The early wins that share significant infrastructure with the next wave of intermediate utility will become strong incumbents (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; Coinbase building decentralized exchanges or custody solutions).  This pattern of early winners serving as the breadmaker for the entire space (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; Binance has a ten-figure war chest and is reinvesting in the ecosystem) will repeat until mainstream adoption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the target end user changes while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Crossing-Chasm-Marketing-High-Tech-Mainstream/dp/0060517123&quot;&gt;crossing the chasm&lt;/a&gt;, it’s like a repeated game of musical chairs where previous round winners have an advantage, but nothing is won until the final version of usefulness is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;short-term-embracing-timing-ambiguity&quot;&gt;Short-term: Embracing timing ambiguity.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the entropic adoption path, ethos-charged black/white challenges of asking, “you don’t think Bitcoin is better than fiat?”, “you don’t think web3 is more trustworthy than Google?”, “you don’t think decentralized finance is better than JP Morgan?” are not productive to seeking the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of asking what will come true vs not come true, it may be more fruitful to ponder which path may catalyze the others?  It’s probably just a matter of timing.  1 year vs 4 years vs 10 years vs 25 years are &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; different outcomes in building/investing, so this is the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessing-whats-next&quot;&gt;Assessing what’s next.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conceptual framework above should help any of us begin to assess the value proposition, the customer and their needs.  From there, it is up to the each of us to interpret the potential size of each market and how compelling each thesis is.  I’d love to see more analytical follow ups, but the below is my intuitive take:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sound-money-is-here-to-stay&quot;&gt;Sound money is here to stay.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Money is simply a ledger of who owns how much of something.  And weirdly enough what it fundamentally requires is that others are willing to exchange goods/services with it and hold it.  (2) Perhaps more importantly, we’ve built incredibly efficient and borderless information sharing and consumption platforms over the past two decades (such as search, social media and instant messaging).  &lt;strong&gt;Those two points combined has made now a uniquely compelling time to experiment with a concept of decentralized digital money.&lt;/strong&gt;  It is now faster and more inexpensive than ever to create an idea and to share it virally with the world, and now that money can be money.  Still mind-boggling to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike web3 or open finance, the money use case only requires belief and reasonable scalability to succeed.  As such, the ingredients for success are already within reach.  The rest is up to what consumers decide, what regulators decide and how the community decides to communicate the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why one of the few high conviction beliefs available today is that the concept of a non-sovereign (or perhaps pan-sovereign) digital money is here to stay (whether that is Bitcoin, Ethereum or something else entirely).  The hurdles here around scalability, awareness, wealth distribution, regulatory framework seem reasonable compared to the demand of the expanding core customer base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If hypothesis above is correct, &lt;strong&gt;crypto-enabled businesses that support adjacent services for the decentralized store of value will be highly valuable&lt;/strong&gt; (insurance, custody, security and any other UIs and managed services on top of the core protocol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One aspect of this thesis I’m passionate about is wealth distribution (and surprisingly one of my most contrarian positions).  &lt;strong&gt;Because the value of money changes throughout its adoption cycle, I believe that wealth distribution is in fact an evolving feature of any money.&lt;/strong&gt;  Wealth distribution is one of the largest sources of long-term fragility for any monetary system.  The converse is also true: &lt;strong&gt;when guided correctly, it be a source of unstoppable growth and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antifragility&quot;&gt;antifragility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  I believe this will be one of the most productive areas for experiments in crypto going forward (more on this on another post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;web3-faces-a-high-bar-for-adoption&quot;&gt;Web3 faces a high bar for adoption.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the social need for an Internet without abuse of centralized control must absolutely recognized, &lt;strong&gt;the customer-focused framework paints a challenging view of the adoption path today&lt;/strong&gt;.  It has a (very important but) small customer base with a strong need, trying to reach an audience that is already satisfied by (addicted to?) incumbent platforms.  This was one of the difficult realizations, especially as someone who is passionate about the tenets of web3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At feature parity, people will choose trust, but most people are not likely to sacrifice the convenience they have today for “trust insurance”&lt;/strong&gt; (unless there’s an high-profile event that eventually turns the pubilc narrative).  The fundamental challenge here is the asymmetric cost/benefit for the censored vs their target audience.  The broader audience is used to the benefits of a smooth, quick and managed experience that delivers the information that they enjoy (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; dopamine hits, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2017/feb/04/twitter-accounts-really-are-echo-chambers-study-finds&quot;&gt;worldview corroborating information&lt;/a&gt;) quickly and effortlessly.  While people all claim they enjoy “good” ethos and “healthy” things, behavior tends to indicate otherwise (vices and impulses dominate internet services).  So the people that are censored want web3, but the people that aren’t censored are already on web2, and––despite potential issues (of fake news, irresponsible data custody etc)––it unfortunately works well for most people on most days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, intermediate utility may be more difficult to achieve here due to the nature of the atomic unit of success for a network participant.  Money interactions are comprised of independent one-to-one transactions being offered and settled, whereas data interactions (web, Internet usage) are often comprised of many concurrent one-to-many data consumption feeds happening at once.  More specifically, money (sound money / open finance) interactions are focused on &lt;em&gt;write operations&lt;/em&gt; (making a transaction changes state) and business model scales with writes (% of transaction value or # of transactions), whereas Internet/data interactions are focused on &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;operations&lt;/em&gt; (serving an Instagram photo or an article to a user) and the business model scales with reads (eyeballs → ads, subscriptions or equivalent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s worth considering if and why the web3 ethos must be coupled with blockchain technology&lt;/strong&gt;;  having a clear articulation of this would certainly be helpful regardless of one’s views on the topic.  For example, it’s fascinating to see (a) the “bring your own data” approach of &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockstack.org/&quot;&gt;Blockstack&lt;/a&gt; and (b) the no blockchain &amp;amp; pure gossip protocol approach of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scuttlebutt.nz/&quot;&gt;Secure Scuttlebutt&lt;/a&gt; getting much less attention than Ethereum.  There’s also an open question of whether compensating participants for economic value generated in the network requires a blockchain or if incumbents can serve that user demand without employing a public blockchain (will think more about this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a social/public goods point of view, this is an incredible movement that should be supported in continuing to experiment with different architectures for information organization and propagation.  It’s also possible that there is an alternate architecture that could compete with today’s “fullstack” approach (decentralize all the layers, apps, infra).  For example, a sound money + centralized services that is compatible with a non-blockchain web3 solution using a p2p gossip protocol is entirely technically possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all said, I believe that the companies that are working on web3 are fighting for an important ethos of empowering the user and building public utilities that serve everyone.  &lt;strong&gt;That is undoubtedly an ethos worth fighting for&lt;/strong&gt;, and I’m hopeful that the mission will help these teams navigate the idea maze to the right place, even if the path isn’t crystal clear today.  The teams working hard on valuable infrastructure R&amp;amp;D will always have an essential role to play in the broader ecosystem, no matter what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-open-finance-idea-maze&quot;&gt;The Open Finance Idea Maze&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And within in a maze, there’s another maze.  Welcome to the recursive crypto maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bearer Instruments vs Registered Instruments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to articulating the value proposition and challenges of open finance comes down to understanding the concept of bearer instruments vs registered instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bearer_instrument&quot;&gt;bearer instrument&lt;/a&gt; gives legal claims over the provided rights (voting, yield, etc.) to whomever holds the instrument. A registered instrument’s legal claims are managed by a trusted intermediary who administers the rights of the instrument on behalf of the legal holder (and those registered owners simply hold a certificate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a bearer instrument, you don’t need to trust anyone, with a registered instrument, you need to trust that they will stand by your interests in good times and bad.  On the flip side, with a bearer instrument, if you lose it, there’s no one you can go to for help.  With a registered instrument, losing a certificate means you just go to the intermediary and get another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a non-reversible digital bearer asset, essentially like cash; whoever holds it owns it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was beautifully designed in the sense that the features that it prioritized made it uniquely fit to serve well as a digital bearer asset.  No identity requirement, no charge backs. &lt;strong&gt;Instant settlement.&lt;/strong&gt;  The digital bearer asset use case has the unique quality that all components of the transaction are present at one moment in time (no future promises to fulfill).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Debt, Equity &amp;amp; Open Finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debt and equity capital are driving forces of the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With credit, we can stake our reputation to get resources today and pay someone back tomorrow.  If we’re successful and honest, we pay the lender back with interest.  However, if we’re either not successful or not honest, we are held accountable by some other authority at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With equity, we can give/sell part ownership of an enterprise to get resources today, and in return we promise it will be a more valuable asset tomorrow.  If we fail and were honest, no harm, no foul.  However, if we’re a bad actor in our role as a fiduciary, we’re held accountable by some other authority at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most such securities are registered instruments, not bearer instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money vs Securities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because credit and equity retain value over specific scenarios over a period of time, reputation and identity are far more important than in an instant settlement instrument such as cash or Bitcoin, which are intended for use cases where all terms of transaction are known and present at the time of the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of money does not depend on the action of the previous holder or transaction (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; the previous holder of your $100 bill cannot somehow affect the value of the note once it’s in your hands), but only on the action of the one central authority that manages your entire economy.  So money is a unique bearer asset that depends on only one thing to retain value: trust in the money’s administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, registered securities (equities, credit, property) require not only the faith in the law (property rights, security laws etc of the issuing jurisdiction) but also the good faith of their counterparty.  This is likely why users will continue to demand registered instruments that provide that protection as a service for the security owner.  Therefore, while sound money doesn’t require active participation from a government, most forms of real asset on a blockchain require integration of credible enforcement (examples include binding legal contracts that refer to Colored Coins or ERC20 tokens that represent property title).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finding the right markets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consideration here is that meaningful adoption will most likely happen first in frontier markets and not developed markets.  Developed markets have fairly mature financial infrastructure, which makes the bar for change much higher.  Compelling open finance use cases will be enabling basic forms of lending, commerce, identity in frontier markets that lack identity systems and already use foreign currency as store of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bottoms up vs incumbent consortiums&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a thought exercise, the alternative outcome can be studied by what happened with Visa.  Visa started as a non-profit owned by banks as credit card infrastructure for that consortium, and now it’s more valuable than all but one of the individual banks (Visa $323B, JPMorgan $385B).  As such, an open-finance consortium led by various banks and Internet giants (anyone with distribution and regulatory edge) would be a credible player to compete for a version of the open finance vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not ideal solution from the “crypto native” point of view.  However, we cannot ignore the possibility of banks and Internet giants raising the bar for minimum viable usefulness just enough to make the upstarts less compelling on a relative basis (the bar for fintech in the US is becoming higher as we speak with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nacha.org/rules/same-day-ach-moving-payments-faster-phase-1&quot;&gt;same day ACH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marcus.com/us/en&quot;&gt;high-yield savings acct by Goldman&lt;/a&gt;, various &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.varomoney.com/&quot;&gt;mobile-first banks&lt;/a&gt;).  In fact, some giants are considering competing on blockchain technology directly (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2018/5/8/17329696/facebook-blockchain-crypocurrency-david-marcus-crypto-messenger-app&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/goldman-sachs-is-reportedly-mulling-a-cryptocurrency-custody-service/&quot;&gt;Goldman&lt;/a&gt;) or by tapping into its ethos (&lt;a href=&quot;http://tomtunguz.com/airbnb-shares/&quot;&gt;Airbnb shares for top hosts&lt;/a&gt;).  This argument extends to sovereign states as well (China could launch RMBCoin faster than US launches TreasuryCoin), and try and take a crack at creating the open standard for identity &amp;amp; financial infrastructure in countries that don’t have it yet (SEAsia and Africa).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, open finance represents some of the most complex parts of the crypto maze today.   It will be interesting to discuss startups vs giants, developed vs frontier market components of the infrastructure/adoption in another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section does not seek to argue the merits of one thesis over another but instead is an exercise in clarifying my own thinking.  I’m curious to hear what you think, but before you get too excited or offended, let’s discuss (1) assumptions that could significantly change the intuitions above and (2) how we can contribute from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenging-assumptions&quot;&gt;Challenging Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth discussing what assumptions could change and change the implications of the cognitive dissonance discussed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Value created by base layer is in excess of the inefficiency of the added layers.”&lt;/em&gt;  I find this argument difficult to believe because that would likely manifest in a thriving decentralized base layer and centralized trusted services specialized around that base layer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Tech reaches feature/SLA parity over time.”&lt;/em&gt;  This argues that tradeoffs at base layer could become much less expensive due to technological breakthroughs.  This will certainly be directionally correct at most points in time as research continues; effective replication factor of data, cost/time of nodes discovery, and data routing will most certainly decrease over time.  However, the more important question is if and when it can come down enough to make up for the UX gap for even the motivated user (then continuing to the average user).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Modularity of services and checks &amp;amp; balances provide value to the participant.”&lt;/em&gt;  For example, a version of the US that is run by one dictator that runs all three branches of government would certainly be more efficient than the checks and balances we have today, but more importantly it would be a fragile equilibrium.  Perhaps the decentralized base layer provides a way for the trusted intermediary services on top of the base layer to have checks &amp;amp; balances, resulting in a net improvement for the user.  This is vague at the moment, but would like to revisit this concept as the infrastructure and products mature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Decreased compliance and human cost.&lt;/em&gt;  The tech itself maybe less efficient than the centralized counterpart, but perhaps reducing the recurring operational cost of intermediation (i.e. compliance backend, and various back office functions of banks)  will provide a net savings.  Cloud infrastructure is optimized for efficiency and lower cost, so the main way to have lower total cost is by tapping into underutilized hardware (zero capex, minimal opex) or by reducing repeated human administration cost of non-core / supporting services.  This is an interesting line of argument worth keeping an eye out for; not enough data points to confirm yet, but it’s possible and if true, revolutionary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-we-contribute-today&quot;&gt;How can we contribute today?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the challenges above and being discouraged is like writing off the Internet in 1990 and saying “this won’t work.”  The productive response is to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://inside.bwater.com/publications/principles_excerpt&quot;&gt;be a hyperrealist&lt;/a&gt;” and approach the solvable problems today.  For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experimentation.&lt;/em&gt;  Continue experimentation on different set of tradeoffs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Sharding-FAQs#this-sounds-like-theres-some-kind-of-scalability-trilemma-at-play-what-is-this-trilemma-and-can-we-break-through-it&quot;&gt;decentralization, scalability, security&lt;/a&gt;), level of abstraction for user interaction, as well as different markets, niches, distribution channels with the goal of mainstream usage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building products that can get ethos-neutral users.&lt;/em&gt;  The first step is to build for ethos-aligned users that are willing to sacrifice UX and evangelize, but the goal should be to build products that can get ethos-neutral users.  People don’t use Google for its algorithm; they use it for its speed in retrieving information they were looking for.  Analogous to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tonysheng.com/privacy-freedom-crypto-anarchy&quot;&gt;how privacy for requires opt-in from people that care for privacy&lt;/a&gt;, decentralized tech requires broad buy-in to compete with incumbents meaningfully.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experiment&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;outside “meatspace.”&lt;/em&gt;  Purely digital assets and experiences may serve as an excellent early beachhead for experimentation.  They have the advantage of not requiring physical or legal enforcement.  For example, the virtual building you built on SimCity could be built with borrowed digital currency secured by another digital building you own in a different part of the game universe.  While this example is purely digital, there could be a path where the infrastructure that powers this economy could be an early test bed for future real estate transactions in the physical realm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experiment in friendlier regulatory environments.&lt;/em&gt;  Singapore and Malta are examples of much friendlier regulatory environments than say the U.S., Japan, China or Korea.  Another example is that certain jurisdictions may treat cryptocurrency related gains/losses differently with respect to taxes, which may inadvertently create tailwinds for adoption in favorable jurisdictions.  [ I should find a link for implications of positive law––”these are the things that are legal” (and everything else is not)––vs negative law––”you must not do this” (but everything else is ok). ]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontier/developing markets.&lt;/em&gt;  Places such as Nigeria, Indonesia, Malaysia, Argentina are attractive environments that have potential for reaching core customers.  Some indications include: more cash-based, less established financial infrastructure and access to products, use of non-native sovereign currency for better stability.  Look for these fundamental indicators of finding core customers (side note: don’t read articles from crypto news sources, too much hype to give you a fair gauge of the traction level).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do research&lt;/em&gt;. build the most efficient and powerful primitives for privacy, decentralized computation etc that makes the correct tradeoffs.  For example:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Storing data.  Decrease replication factor / compute overhead of decentralized architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Retrieving data.  Improve data availability and routing schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Better comms&lt;/em&gt;.  Less fluff, hype, ideology (unless you’re creating base layer money, in which case, meme away my friend) and more product.  Pinpoint which tech feature you are using.  What is new about this feature?  What technical tradeoff or innovation is enabling this new feature?  What product is uniquely enabled by this feature?  Why is this product clearly better than the next best alternative?  How is data encrypted and distributed in plain sight more secure than data stored at Facebook’s data centers?
 Excellent comms is vastly underrated today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Identify customers and markets.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/future-founders-heres-how-to-spot-and-build-in-nonobvious-markets/&quot;&gt;Markets are king&lt;/a&gt;, so identify one where the product can serve deep customer needs (2017 was ideology, curiosity, speculation and promise of riches).  Articulate how a new feature unlocked a new service for a user that outperforms the customer’s current next best alternative.  Now try and pitch it to a skeptical friend.  If it makes sense to them, it’s time to build it and attack that market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crypto community is working incredibly hard to bend the arc of technological adoption towards openness, economic mobility, and networks that serve (rather than extract from) participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that technologies that (1) reduce our reliance on data/value intermediaries and (2) increase the access of financial products that enable wealth generation and global socioeconomic mobility are undoubtedly good, but also valuable for the world.  And when public value is created, it makes it an intrepid time to be an adventurer (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; technologist, entrepreneur or investor).  It will be a fun decade or two as these hypotheses unfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows what will happen, but these are some frameworks that help me think about how the future will unfold.  Uncertainty and lack of consensus can be frustrating or confusing, but that exactly is the opportunity for us to contribute.  I hope the idea maze above helps you in deciding where we should focus our collective energy in order to generate the most promising opportunities for mainstream adoption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions/ideas/responses/challenges, let’s chat!  If you want to collaborate in building and navigating this future, I would love to journey down the crypto maze together. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many thanks to Martin Becze for discussions that led to this post.  Shout out to Jill Carlson, Tony Sheng, Linda Xie, Tom Ding, Zao Yang, Lily Liu for conversations that helped articulate these thoughts.  Thank you Vitalik Buterin for review of historical accounts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Choi</name></author><summary type="html">tl;dr It’s early in the game for crypto, and an idea maze helps us dig deeper and discern between compelling adoption paths and dead ends. Bitcoin then Ethereum catalyzed excitement for “crypto” broadly, and the industry is debating the merits of “sound money,” “web3” and “open finance.” While each share the same ethos of disintermediation, they require different features to succeed and are competing against different alternatives. Inheriting not only the ethos of decentralization but also the technical tradeoffs of its predecessors has resulted in an underlying cognitive dissonance. The way to resolve the dissonance is to forget the familiar narratives, and instead to examine: the novel features of the technology, who the core customers are, who is failing to serve them now and why there can be a compelling new product today. Let’s enter the crypto idea maze.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethereum Casper 101</title><link href="https://jonchoi.com/casper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethereum Casper 101" /><published>2017-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://jonchoi.com/Casper101</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jonchoi.com/casper/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jonchoi/ethereum-casper-101-7a851a4f1eb0&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr&lt;/em&gt; Casper will implement proof of stake in Ethereum. We begin with a review on why proof of stake matters and continue with its strengths &amp;amp; weaknesses. This post aims to provide a broad overview of Casper and clarify some of the confusion with respect to the two protocol design efforts related to Casper. The two proposed implementations share the same core design principle: applying cryptoeconomic mechanism design to secure the network while managing challenges regarding liveness, safety and synchrony assumptions. This post is also an overview of the progress so far and the challenges that lie ahead. Most importantly for fellow newcomers, the post identifies &amp;amp; defines key concepts and ties together various helpful resources under one context. The overarching intention is to make Casper and proof of stake more approachable to everyone in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy and please don’t hesitate to reach out with questions, corrections or feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*M7f5y6HY3Y9HRcFGplaFuQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outline
Introduction
Proof of Stake
A Tale of Two Caspers
Why Casper Matters
Design Principles
Challenges
Future Work
Glossary
Conclusion
Introduction
Casper is hardly a new project as it dates back to 2014, so fortunately it has a lot of related information online. However, despite the wealth of information out there, there’s no easy jumping-off point for a beginner to ramp up and start engaging with the project. That’s why I’m writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While other posts, videos and papers focus on the specification, implementation and verification of Casper. This post focuses on the various guiding design principles of Casper, how it differs from competing approaches, why you should care about it, and how you can contribute to this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, Casper has maintained an exceptionally open and collaborative culture among Ethereum researchers, developers and community members. I hope this post can continue that tradition by introducing you to Casper and convincing you why it’s important to Ethereum as well as the larger public blockchain ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, this post is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick and broad introduction to PoS and Casper.
Discussion on why Casper matters, its design principles and its challenges.
A list of key resources and terms to get you started with PoS and Casper.
This is not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full history of Casper.
Specification of Casper.
Implementation details of Casper.
Formal verification of Casper.
If this is review for you, a list of resources are linked throughout the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I hope you enjoy this beginner-friendly introduction to Casper: Ethereum’s proof of stake research and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof of Stake
(If you’re already familiar, please feel free to skip ahead to the next section: “What is Casper?”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof of Stake (PoS) is a category of consensus algorithms for public blockchains that depend on a validator’s economic stake in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In proof of work (PoW) based public blockchains (e.g. Bitcoin and the current implementation of Ethereum), the algorithm rewards participants who solve cryptographic puzzles in order to validate transactions and create new blocks (i.e. mining). In PoS-based public blockchains (e.g. Ethereum’s upcoming Casper implementation), a set of validators take turns proposing and voting on the next block, and the weight of each validator’s vote depends on the size of its deposit (i.e. stake). Validators are rewarded for their service to the network, but the stake also acts as an economic disincentive for bad actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant advantages of PoS include security, reduced risk of centralization, and energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explicit Economic Security
In PoW, your downside is capped at how much energy cost and hardware depreciation you incur and therefore has an implicit cost that adjusts dynamically (via 10 min block time target). While PoS has its own challenges (discussed later in the post), one of its major strengths is the flexibility to explicitly design the penalties of Byzantine behavior (i.e. not following the protocol). This gives the protocol designer increased control over dialing in the “shape” of the asymmetric risk &amp;amp; reward profile of various actions within the network. One proxy for security is the cost of doing damage to the utility and correctness of the network, and therefore the ability to have explicit penalties (perhaps at levels that are more draconian than PoW) can increase the security of the network (i.e. economic security).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note, Vitalik further argues that PoS has better recovery properties. In PoW, there’s an issue of “spawn camp” attacks that can render a blockchain unusable. In PoS, the network can delete the attacker’s stake and prevent repeated attacks. The economic analysis further clarifies this concept. The marginal cost of repeated attack is the same as the first round in PoS. Whereas in PoW, the main marginal cost for another round during a 51% attack is the power cost (the incremental hardware depreciation &amp;amp; physical space cost is minimal for repeated attacks). To drive the point home, let’s paraphrase Vlad Zamfir, the cost profile of a repeated 51% attack in PoS is as if “your ASIC farm burned down” with each additional round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitigation of Centralization
Proof of Stake mitigates the impact of economies of scale in making consensus. In proof of work, we can already see that the network trusts a relatively concentrated set of mining pools (e.g. AntPool) to secure the network. Larger proof of work mining pools can lower the unit cost of their technical and operational infrastructure (datacenter costs, power costs, personnel) by both (1) amortizing a fixed cost over a larger operation and (2) having bargaining power by operating as a larger entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that two sets of mining pools with equal economic cost, one may be able to achieve a higher hash rate and have more influence in the network, dollar for dollar. For example, 10,000 miners that each spend $1/min ($87.6M/yr) may have less hashing power than one mining pool that spends $10,000/min (despite also spending $87.6M/yr). (Further work: quantifying the benefits to centralization in PoW mining would be fascinating. i.e. is it 1bps, 1% or multiples in hashing power per dollar invested?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in proof of stake, a dollar is a dollar. The benefit here is that you can’t pool together to make a dollar worth more. Nor can you develop or buy application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs) to have an advantage technologically. So, PoS intends to mitigate the regressive distribution of PoW mining rewards and move directionally towards proportional distribution. (Going beyond proportional to progressive distribution will require mature decentralized reputation/identity management services).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy Efficiency
Proof of work relies on wasting resources to secure the network. Bitcoin currently uses over 20 TWh per year of power, which is close to the power consumption by the entire country of Ecuador. In order for Bitcoin to have broader adoption and operate at Visa’s scale, it would have to waste as much power as a much larger country. Extrapolating it’s current pace, one can see why proof of work may not be a sustainable path forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bitcoin may serve an important social function that may indeed exceed its financial costs and environmental externalities (i.e. Nick Szabo’s social scalability argument), proponents of PoS believe it is possible to replicate the incentive mechanisms of a PoW blockchain without wasting as much energy (by orders of magnitude). Alternatively, some may argue there exists a price of negative externalities where even the benefits of social scalability might be outweighed by the environmental costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the exact answer is hard to ascertain a priori, I believe the crypto ecosystem as a whole has the responsibility to explore all promising consensus mechanisms to weigh their pros/cons and feasibility. (For example, it’s great that other projects are testing the benefits and feasibility of various forms of proof of storage, among others.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, it’s also worth noting the two kinds of costs to PoW issuance. There are internalized costs, which are paid by miners and passed on to currency holders. Then there are externalized costs, such as the environmental costs and subsidies from governments (most likely in the form of cheaper electricity). In PoS, there are low consensus costs (no power &amp;amp; hardware costs), which allows for low issuance. As the network matures, it may even allow for negative issuance (net of burned tx fees as well as any penalties and slashing), which can have a price-stabilizing effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, not only is lower energy consumption better for the environment but it also enables simpler mechanism design. That is because lower energy consumption allows for substituting realized costs (power and depreciation costs are nonreversible) with potential economic value-at-loss (i.e. believable risk of unrealized costs) in order to secure the network. This is a key underlying hypothesis of PoS: both realized costs and prospect of losing money can incentivize participants to secure the network. Therefore–while difficult–it is possible (and thus preferable) to secure public blockchains via loss aversion, which can decrease the public costs and deadweight losses in a system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof of Stake: Summary
That sums up the main benefits of PoS. While Casper provides specific benefits to Ethereum (discussed below), a significant portion of its importance are the general benefits of PoS: explicit economic security, mitigation of centralization and energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now that we’ve discussed PoS, let’s dive into Casper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading on PoS
Proof of Stake FAQ in Ethereum wiki
Proof of Stake Design Philsophy by Vitalik Buterin
Critique of PoS by Tuur Demeester (and comments 1, 2, 3)
Tendermint Whitepaper by Jae Kwon
Cryptocurrencies without Proof of Work by Iddo Bentov et al. (Slides)
Bitcoin Wiki on Proof of Stake
Select examples: Tendermint, Polkadot, Peercoin.
A Tale of Two Caspers
In simple terms, Casper is Ethereum’s Proof of Stake work stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casper is not a specific implementation but a family of two main projects under active research by the Ethereum team. Informally, there’s “Vitalik’s Casper” aka Casper FFG and “Vlad’s Casper” aka Casper CBC (explained below). This subtlety isn’t clear until you start diving deep into Casper materials online, which can be very confusing to the “uninitiated.” (In fact, that is a main motivator for this post). While independent implementations, they have the same goal in mind: moving Ethereum over to proof of stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Despite a surprisingly common impression that Ethereum is already implementing PoS, it is still a PoW chain (using ethash). While being memory hard and more ASIC-resistant than Bitcoin, Ethereum is a PoW chain nonetheless and has the same drawbacks with respect to energy efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that, let’s briefly discuss the two Caspers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FFG vs CBC
Caveat: both of these projects will present more detailed papers and proof of concepts the weeks following Devcon3, but here’s a quick preview of their approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casper the Friendly Finality Gadget (“FFG”) — aka “Vitalik’s Casper” — is a hybrid PoW/PoS consensus mechanism, which is the immediate candidate for Ethereum’s first bridge to proof of stake. More specifically, FFG implements a proof of stake mechanism as an overlay on top of a proof of work chain (such as Ethereum’s ethash PoW chain). Simply, the blockchain would grow every block with the familiar ethash PoW algorithm, but every 50 blocks is a PoS “checkpoint” where finality is assessed via a network of validators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casper the Friendly GHOST: Correct-by-Construction (“CBC”) — aka “Vlad’s Casper”—differs in approach from traditional protocol design: (1) the protocol is partially specified in the beginning and (2) and the rest of the protocol is derived in a way that is proven to satisfy the desired/requisite properties (typically protocol is fully defined then tested to satisfy the said properties). In this case, one way to derive the full protocol is to implement an estimate safety oracle (“an ideal adversary”), which either raises exceptions of a fault of a justified estimate or enumerates the potential future faulty estimates. More specifically, Vlad’s work focuses on designing protocols where one can extend local views of a node’s estimate of safety to achieve consensus safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, FFG focuses more on a multi-step transition to introducing PoS for the Ethereum network. This prepares for an iterative implementation that increases the role of PoS in the network over time. (PoS will claim a smaller portion of the rewards to start). In contrast, CBC focuses on formal methods that derive safety proofs “by construction” from first principles. Albeit confusing, the different approaches to solving this problem created two distinct work streams that complement each other well. The final form of Casper will likely draw from learnings from both FFG and CBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next steps
While substantial progress was achieved, many of the details — both at the higher mechanism design level and at the lower implementation level — remain to be finalized. This is openly acknowledged by both Vitalik and Vlad, and this can be an invitation for more of the community to engage to move the conversation forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sum, both research projects are very active, and more updates should be available at Devcon3 in November. The role of this overview does not include going into more detail, but please feel free to dive into more implementation and design details in the links below (This doc will likely be updated or followed up once FFG and CBC papers are released).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links for FFG
Casper FFG Basics Paper by Vitalik Buterin and Virgil Griffith (Draft)
Casper Github Repo (FFG)
Karl Floersch’s FFG Implementation on pyethereum
Further Reading on FFG
Simple explanation on Reddit by Vitalik Buterin. August 2017.
Minimal Slashing Conditions by Vitalik Buterin. March 2017.
Safety Under Dynamic Validator Sets by Vitalik Buterin. March 2017.
Slasher by Vitalik Buterin. January 2014.
Weak Subjectivity by Vitalik Buterin. November 2014.
On Settlement Finality by Vitalik Buterin. May 2016.
Triangle of Harm by Vitalik Buterin. July 2017.
Casper Economic Incentives Overview by Karl Floersch. Sept 2017.
Formal Methods on Another Casper by Yoichi Hirai.
Github. ethereum/casper.
Links for CBC
Will be updated after Devcon3
Further Reading on CBC
Casper CBC CESC deck and video by Vlad Zamfir. September 2017.
Casper CBC EDCON deck by Vlad Zamfir. (Video part 1, part 2) February 2017.
Devcon2 CBC Casper Deck and video by Vlad Zamfir. October 2016.
2016.12.06 History of Casper: Chapter 1 by Vlad Zamfir — How Vlad started working on Ethereum and PoS. Slasher and deposits (Mar 2013 — Sep 2014)
2016.12.07 History of Casper: Chapter 2 by Vlad Zamfir — Nothing-at-stake. Bribing attack. Long range attack. Game theory and security research. (Fall 2014)
2016.12.11 History of Casper: Chapter 3 by Vlad Zamfir — Finality. Synchronicity Assumptions. Slashing Conditions. Tendermint. (Sep ’14 — Dec ’14)
2016.12.12 History of Casper: Chapter 4 by Vlad Zamfir — Cooperative Game Theory. Oligopolies. How Casper is different than other PoS consensus designs. (Dec’14 — Jan ’15)
2016.12.30 History of Casper: Chapter 5 by Vlad Zamfir — Censorship. Defining decentralization. Availability vs Consistency. Friendly GHOST (Feb ’15 — March ’15)
History of Casper series is to be continued…
Why Casper Matters
Now that we have decoded what this mysterious Casper project is. Let’s synthesize what we learned about PoS and Casper to understand why this matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple terms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization (covered in PoS)
Energy efficiency (covered in PoS)
Explicit Economic Security (covered in PoS)
Scaling Ethereum
Gentle Transition from PoW
Because of Proof of Stake
The first three points are covered in the Proof of Stake section. However, it is worth mentioning that at ~$28B, Ethereum is the second largest cryptocurrency and represents ~18% of the total market cap of the space. So any incremental decentralization and gains in energy efficiency can have a non-trivial impact today and a very significant impact in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a review, (1) PoS has less available economies of scale because — “dollar for dollar” — a miner/validator can’t achieve outsized influence on the network. In PoW, a large mining pool might get more hashing power per dollar than an individual miner, whereas in PoS, a dollar is a dollar, which will likely mitigate the centralizing forces in mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And (2) whereas PoW relies on energy wastage for network security, PoS relies on the potential of losing a deposit for network security. The challenge then becomes (3) how we mimic (and enhance) the positive features of PoW and mitigate the weaknesses of PoS with economic mechanism design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of Scaling
Next, let’s talk about something new: (4) scaling. The key to understanding this is two-fold: (a) Casper is about establishing explicit finality (as opposed to probabilistic finality) and (b) explicit finality enables maintaining network security while scaling via sharding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In PoW chains, finality is implicit (just as “skin in the game” is implicit via power wastage). The implicit nature of finality in PoW chains is apparent when you examine how transactions are finalized in real use cases. Depending on the magnitude and importance of the payment, you wait for additional number of block confirmations (number of block times since a transaction appears in the longest chain). For example, for a coffee, you might be okay with a few confirmations, but for buying a car, you may need more than the average number of confirmations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Casper provides a concept of explicit finality. For example, Casper FFG begins to overlay finality on top of the PoW chain. So the underlying chain continues to have an implicit way of determining how final a transaction is. However, Casper FFG provides explicit finality after about 2.5 “epoch times.” (Each epoch time being a sequence of 50 PoW blocks. A checkpoint is the last block in an epoch. It is first “justified” then “finalized” by a validator set. More details available in the paper linked above and potentially a future post.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, with certain Byzantine Fault Tolerance assumptions, we can be sure that either our assumptions have been violated or that the checkpoint is final. Since we are also aware of the validator set a priori (which can also be dynamic), bad actors are penalized through fault attribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does this relate to sharding &amp;amp; scalability? Having this explicit finality allows more flexibility in how much (more accurately, how little) each node in the network has to do. Having more regular explicit finality allows further exploration of questions such as: what if not every node had to hold all of the state or all of the transactions? what if not every node had to validate every transaction? These questions of having heterogenous “responsibilities” of nodes in public blockchains are tackled by a workstream around blockchain sharding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to go back to the point, if we are to explore each node in the network “doing less” or “knowing less,” it is hugely beneficial to consider only the past few epochs of finality rather than the entire probabilistic chain since the genesis block. Therefore, at this epoch time interval, finality doesn’t actually help with confirming a simple transaction, since transactions clear in number of confirmations fewer than the epoch time. Instead, finality will enable public blockchains to scale beyond the current ~10 transactions per second to larger orders of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Ethereum is worth ~$28B
The final point is (5) a gentle transition from PoW. Here’s the context for newcomers such as myself. Ethereum’s explicit goals to move to PoS predates the significant increase in the value of ether this year. The plan is to start with a hybrid PoS overlay on top of the ethash PoW chain and to ramp up gradually towards “pure” PoS. Given the significant increase in ETH network value, this gradual transition to PoS is a prudent strategy to prevent potential value destruction while transitioning a significant piece of the underlying Ethereum infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading
Sharding FAQ, Ethereum wiki
On Slow and Fast Block Times by Vitalik
Design Principles
This is a collection of design principles found in various posts by Vlad and Vitalik. Currently, the guiding design principles for Casper are scattered around various resources. Hope reading them in one go provides more clarity on the overall design principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics to design behavior. Explicit economic mechanism design can achieve implicit economic incentives found in other social contracts (i.e. consensus protocols like proof of work). If you like analogies, search “big games” in History of Casper part 3.
Maximize cost of attack. For example, the amount of damage that an attacker can do to a protocol’s utility should be bound by some “griefing factor.” In order to do $100 of damage, it shouldn’t cost $0.01. It should hopefully cost in the order of $100. In other words, we want to minimize the “attack multiple” of each dollar used for attacking the protocol (more on this coming in another post).
Public cost-benefit, not just private. Protocol economics should account for social (i.e. “public”) cost &amp;amp; benefit (negative and positive externalities) as we begin scaling public blockchains. Energy cost, environmental impact and wealth distribution are some notable examples.
Prevent economies of scale. Centralization weakens the main value proposition of public blockchains. Preventing economies of scale prevents those centralizing factors and build more secure blockchains.
Network security is derived from “skin in the game.” Simple yet worth reiterating. The more you have to lose, the more we can trust you as a validator. Whereas burning energy secures proof of work chains, “putting up economic value-at-loss” secures proof of stake chains.
Design for oligopolies. Cooperative game theory is the name of the game as a protocol won’t be able to fully mitigate the inherent centralizing forces (e.g. economies of scale) in a network. This means analyzing all edge cases that involve self-interested cartel behavior. Notably, a protocol should disincentivize cartels from bullying non-cartel validators (i.e. be “friendly”)
Accountable safety. Design that makes it possible to attribute faults to bad actors as much as possible. Casper relies on the ability to slash attributable Byzantine behavior.
Plausible liveness. Design that doesn’t allow attackers to block the chain from continuing to propose and vote on checkpoints/blocks. This is where Casper differs from other implementations such as Tendermint, which will “lock up” if safety isn’t achieved synchronously.
Minimal synchronicity assumptions. To allow for liveness and “unblock” the chain growing, Casper has minimal synchronicity assumptions. In fact, we expect nodes to log on as infrequently as every couple of months.
Decentralized things should be able to regenerate. A protocol is decentralized only if it can fully recover from the permanent removal of all but one of its nodes. Availability, not just consistency (Again, Tendermint is susceptible to getting “blocked” and cannot regenerate; the validator set for each branch can keep getting smaller per Matthew Wampler-Doty and Vlad’s observation)
Disincentivize censorship. The major tradeoff is that validators have a new attack vector by deliberately going offline. However, cartel censorship is the greater evil here. Choosing the right relative cost of censorship vs. rewards and other penalties (as a % of deposits) will be the key to getting this right.
Further Reading
PoS Design Philosophy
History of Casper (links above)
Challenges
Broader list of Ethereum challenges are available here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenges for Proof of Stake
Nothing-at-stake problem — If there’s a fork in the chain, the optimal strategy for any validator is to validate on every chain, so that the validator gets their reward regardless of the outcome of the fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long range attack — Same mechanism as 51% attack (make a longer chain that rewrites the ledger in the attacker’s favor), but instead of starting the attack 6 blocks back, go much further back in the chain’s history (i.e. 60,000 blocks). This is a problem for PoS since there’s no proof of work (or equivalent time-intensive operation) required to rewrite a very long chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two main challenges are solved via ideas from slasher (and its improved variations). The main points are that (1) validators are known, which allow for fault attribution at a validator level and (2) by having “slashing conditions” that strongly disincentivize certain actions, it is possible to mitigate these issues. Again, this example is crucial in understanding the Casper team’s view on consensus algorithm design: we can leverage economic mechanism design to a secure distributed system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criticisms of Proof of Stake
Adverse selection — Given the potentially draconian penalties, many average or risk-averse “candidate validators” may stay away from participating as a validator. Then, one may argue people with more to gain by “gaming the system” are more likely to join as a validator. More broadly, one may claim that — on average — a good actor may never have a better ROI than a bad actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Response: 
This falls under future work and an area of great focus for the research team: cryptoeconomics. As the parametrization of the mechanism is progresses, the team will iterate on optimizing the constants the balance the risk reward tradeoffs as well as their proportion to the size of the deposits and the action of others (Byzantine behavior).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth mentioning that this problem is also existent (albeit to a lesser degree given the nature of proof of work) in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The rich get richer” — Another common concern when people hear “a consensus algorithm based on how much money you’re staking” is that this may exacerbate wealth inequality within the crypto ecosystem as well as more broadly in the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Response: 
The main takeaway here should be that Proof of Stake is considerably more egalitarian (i.e. gives less benefit to having more capital) than the incumbent Proof of Work based algorithm of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As discussed in the Proof of Stake overview above, PoS mitigates economies of scale, which diminishes the centralizing force among miners. Again, in PoS, a dollar is a dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, against the fair intuition that PoS can exacerbate wealth inequality, it is in fact a non-trivial improvement on the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick aside: In order to have diseconomies of scale or progressive wealth distributions in PoS (one more degree of counteracting wealth inequality), I posit that it is necessary to have mature and reliable identity or reputation systems. Otherwise, larger pools of money will have “sybil behavior” that spreads their wealth over many “less wealthy” false identities that will collectively capture the benefits of a progressive reward system. However, this challenge is out of scope for Casper and will be faced further down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions/Concerns around Casper
“It’s confusing to have multiple Caspers.”
Sorry about that! This post aims to lessen the cognitive dissonance around that fact. But to review, Casper is Ethereum’s family of PoS research and implementations. These work streams will likely converge, but the nature of protocol research requires forking sometimes to explore various approaches until deciding on the best way forward. Things tend to get more complex before they get simpler 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How does Casper differ from Tendermint?” 
The simplified answer here is that Casper focuses on liveness (availability) and can accept less immediate safety (correctness). While Tendermint is a great project, its downside is that the chain will stall if a checkpoint doesn’t have 2/3 of the votes. That is one of the reasons why Ethereum is working on Casper rather than working off of Tendermint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote Vlad Zamfir:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tendermint favours consistency over availability, Casper favours availability over consistency (see the CAP theorem).
Tendermint doesn’t punish online validators for potentially censoring potentially-actually-just-offline validators.
For further reading on this topic: Hudson Jameson’s explanation this quote, reddit discussion featuring Vitalik &amp;amp; Jae Kwon, and the Tendermint whitepaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ 😱 You’re going to change the engine of a live $28B network?” 
Yes, that is very ambitious and daunting. However, moving to PoS was the intent since the early days, and one of the guiding principles of the project. The community members were very much aware of Ethereum’s plans to switch to PoS (i.e. refer to Ethereum Ice Age — the PoW chain difficult adjustment to encourage migration to PoS — which is commonly known in the ecosystem).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should go without saying, but the team will be rolling out the change in stages with the test network. Also, the initial implementation is a hybrid where the PoS elements have less of an economic impact — and therefore impact on security — than in the eventual “pure” PoS consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In practice, transactions are cleared in 10 blocks. Why does finality matter over a 50 block epoch?”
We covered this above, but let’s go over this once again since it’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Casper enables sharding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was very unclear to me in the beginning, but that’s because we need to take a step back from Casper for a moment. Ethereum has many goals, but one of them is to provide a scalable blockchain solution, both technically and environmentally. Ethereum is building for a world where cryptocurrencies have a larger place in the global economy and grow by many orders of magnitude. In that vision, Casper aims to prevent the wasted energy of PoW mining but we still need to scale Ethereum technically. That project is largely encompassed under sharding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, every node in the network does everything. Sharding explores various ways to decrease the average responsibility of each node. The details are out of scope of this post, but an example might be to pose the question: “are there ways to create a new mechanism, where only small subset of nodes verifies each transaction?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The takeaway is that the periodic finality provided by Casper will mitigate lower security related to implementing sharding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, explicit finality allows for a consistency-favoring blockchain. To quote Vitalik:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a PoW chain, if there is, for example, a geth/parity consensus split, then both chains keep growing, and exchanges running one client or the other risk finalizing deposits on a bad chain. But if exchanges wait for Casper finality, then in a 50/50 split it’s likely &lt;em&gt;neither&lt;/em&gt; chain will finalize. This increases the safety of the platform, as in extreme circumstances it “defaults toward finalizing nothing” rather than finalizing &lt;em&gt;the wrong thing&lt;/em&gt;.
In sum, contrary to intuition, explicit finality matters less for transaction clearing and more for blockchain scalability and safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future Work
Execution
Finalizing the design of FFG and CBC.
Implementing proof of concept code.
Deploying into test nets.
“The One Casper”
Thinking about about the final state of Casper PoS. How to leverage concepts from both FFG and CBC to converge on a final state that is compelling, secure and elegant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parameter Optimization
For a given mechanism, optimize parameters and constants for intended incentivization. Iterate on mechanism design with findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community Education
Writing more about the thought process beyond various research work streams to keep engaging with Ethereum, PoS and broader crypto communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Potential Future Posts
History of Casper Part 6
Deep dive into how Casper enables sharding
Deep dive into how and why Casper is different from competing designs
Non-monetary measures of “stake” and “skin in the game” (i.e. $10,000 is worth more to average person than billionaire)
Griefing Factor Analysis 2.0
Glossary
We covered a lot of concepts in this post, and you will run into some other common ones as you dive into the maze of Chrome tabs that will inevitably ensue. Here’s a rough summary of the most helpful and common concepts you need to grok. Hope it helps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof of Stake — a category of consensus algorithms for public blockchains that depend on a validator’s economic stake in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casper — Ethereum’s proof of stake research and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finality — Once an operation in a system completes, the system doesn’t allow for the operation to be reverted (Vitalik on settlement finality). Context: in proof of work, finality is probabilistic and implicit. Casper is designing mechanisms that explicitly enforce finality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fork Choice Rule — A fork choice rule is a function, evaluated by the client, that takes as input the set of blocks and other messages that have been produced, and outputs to the client what the “canonical chain” is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slashing Conditions — Set of rules that, if violated, penalize the validator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sybil Attack — an attack wherein a reputation system is subverted by forging identities in peer-to-peer networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 E’s of Sybil Resistance — 1. Entry Cost 2. Existence Cost 3. Exit Penalty. (coined by Dominic Williams).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing-at-stake problem — A proof of stake implementation challenge that refers to the inherent lack of downside for validating both chains in the case of a fork. It is a well-known problem of proof of stake that is considered solvable. For example, refer to Slasher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bribe attack — Attacker uses a bribe to change the Nash Equilibrium of a validator’s game theory framework to undermine the security of the protocol. (More context in History of Capser pt 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long range attack — Same mechanism as 51% attack (make a longer chain that “rewrote” the ledger in the attacker’s favor), but instead of starting the attack 6 blocks back, go much further back in the chain’s history (think 60,000 blocks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DAG — “Directed Acyclic Graph”. A finite directed graph with no directed cycles. (ETH Stack Exchange).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GHOST — “Greedy Heaviest Observed Subtree.” It’s a chain selection rule with the objective of fast confirmation times while limiting compromises in security or decentralization. (Original Paper, ETH GHOST)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Synchronicity — Refers to the timing assumptions around the messages (i.e. synchronous, partially synchronous and asynchronous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liveness — “Availability.” Protocol-following nodes eventually decide on a value. Opposite would be a network state that is blocked from deciding on a value (i.e. Tendermint without 2/3 votes at a given depth)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safety — “Correctness.” Protocol-following nodes decide on the same value. Another intuitive proxy is whether two conflicting blocks can be committed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FLP Impossibility Theorem — “It’s impossible to have a live, safe and asynchronous network” (formally proven as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accountable Faults — Faults that can be attributed to a specific validator or specific set of validators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byzantine Faults / Byzantine Behavior — Any fault presenting different symptoms to different observers. Non-protocol following behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byzantine Failure — Loss of a system service due to Byzantine faults in a system that requires consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byzantine Fault Tolerance (“BFT”) — Ability for a system to tolerate Byzantine faults. 1/3 Byzantine fault threshold in asynchronous networks. 1/2 in synchronous networks. (BFT consensus algorithms include Paxos, PBFT as well as newer Casper and Tendermint).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nakamoto Consensus — PoW-based bitcoin-style consensus building. Also, Nakamoto-style Consensus exists, which would be chain-based PoS as opposed to BFT-based PoS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tendermint — Proof of Stake implementation that focuses on consistency. Never forks with less than 1/3 malicious actors, but downside is that the chain can stall if a chain lacks 2/3 of the validator votes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validator — An entity that validates checkpoints/blocks of a blockchain for rewards. A miner analog in PoS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validator Set — Set of validators for a given chain at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkpoint — In FFG, it is a block spaced in regular intervals (i.e. every 50 blocks) where the PoS validation mechanism is overlaid on top of the underlying PoW chain (e.g. Ethereum with ethash)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epoch — In FFG, it is a 50 block period where a validator can vote on the finality of its final block (i.e. checkpoint). PoW miners mine blocks and PoS validators validate checkpoints every epoch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Validator Sets — The idea that a blockchain can have changing set of validators throughout a period. Treatment of this is a huge breakthrough in BFT-style consensus algorithms. Tendermint was first notable breakthrough. Casper is also working on this actively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equivocation — The act of a validator sending two messages that conflict with each other (more specific definition on slide 28 of this deck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dunkles — Mechanism that includes data from non-dominant block into the dominant block. This provides better incentive mechanisms and notably helps alleviate the nothing-at-stake problem (link).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proposal Mechanism — Mechanism by which a validator in the set will suggest a block to assess for justification or finalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justification —In FFG for example, 2/3 of a validator set voting on a fresh checkpoint that a checkpoint is the accurate record. This is the intermediary step for a finalized checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finalization — In FFG for example, 2/3 of a validator set voting on a justified checkpoint that a checkpoint is the accurate record. The completion of this step gives a checkpoint finality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State Transition System — A system that maintains a given state (e.g. set of transactions or accounts) and its mutations over time (i.e. transition). Bitcoin, Ethereum, and other public blockchains can be considered state transition systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protocol Utility Function — “…a formula that tells us how well the protocol is doing, that should ideally be calculable from inside the blockchain. In the case of a proof of work chain, this could be the percentage of all blocks produced that are in the main chain. In Casper, protocol utility is zero for a perfect execution where every epoch is finalized and no safety failures ever take place, with some penalty for every epoch that is not finalized, and a very large penalty for every safety failure. If a protocol utility function can be formalized, then penalties for faults can be set as close to the loss of protocol utility resulting from those faults as possible.” (from Triangle of Harm)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
OK, this was a lot of information for a “101,” but now you have all the basics covered and the context to dive into any Casper conversation. My intention in writing this post was (1) to provide an overarching thread of context across the plethora of information out there on Casper, (2) solidify my own understanding of Casper as I dive into cryptoeconomic research for Ethereum scaling (Casper, sharding, gas pricing), (3) to raise awareness and encourage conversation about PoS, Casper and Ethereum and (4) to convince talented mathematicians, economists, computer scientists and developers to start diving into the problems we are trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to dive deeper, dive into the resources linked throughout the post, consider contributing to the future work, and talk to your math, CS, economics, game theory, and distributed systems friends (in and out of crypto) about Ethereum and Casper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve made it this far, thank you for reading. Hope this helped and please reach out with questions, concerns or comments via email or twitter. We would love to hear your feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Vitalik Buterin, Vlad Zamfir, Virgil Griffith and Karl Floersch for discussion and review. All errors remain my own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Choi</name></author><summary type="html">Originally posted on Medium</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A mind trick to write more often</title><link href="https://jonchoi.com/mindtrick/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A mind trick to write more often" /><published>2017-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://jonchoi.com/mindtrick</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jonchoi.com/mindtrick/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jonchoi/a-mind-trick-to-write-more-often-5b5a930b1804&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*XPwkOboJ-YXq2yQkQIDQsw.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been saying I would publish a post for three years now. I would like to wait far shorter to publish, and I would like to articulate my thoughts far more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to encourage that, I will do two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will allow myself the luxury to change my mind. Anything I write reflects my best thought process at the moment but does not define me as a person). This will allow me to write “in the now” and not worry about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective is to share my thoughts, not to measure my skill as a writer. Good writing takes time, and I strive to be a good writer. However, I don’t want that to make me write less often or worry that it’s taking too much time away from my core work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this mind trick works, you’ll be hearing from me more often going forward (hopefully more often than once every three years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, I’m just going to publish this. Doing it live.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jon Choi</name></author><summary type="html">Originally posted on Medium</summary></entry></feed>